<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vinay Hiremath</title>
    <link>https://vinayh.com/tags/life/</link>
    <description></description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 22:37:21 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vinayh.com/tags/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>The Evolution of Trust</title>
        <link>https://vinayh.com/posts/2021-03-13/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 22:37:21 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://vinayh.com/posts/2021-03-13/</guid>
        <description>I found out about this through an acquaintance today, and I would highly recommend checking it out (if it&amp;rsquo;s still accessible here): The Evolution of Trust by Nicky Case
It&amp;rsquo;s a rather playful interactive demonstration of building and undermining trust featuring &amp;ldquo;players&amp;rdquo; that employ simple strategies. For example, in a simple game in which two players both equally gain if they cooperate, but a cheater wins a higher reward if they fail to cooperate while their partner cooperates, which player&amp;rsquo;s strategy wins out?</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lost in translation</title>
        <link>https://vinayh.com/posts/2021-01-19/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 03:41:38 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://vinayh.com/posts/2021-01-19/</guid>
        <description>I sometimes feel like Santiago in &lt;em&gt;The Alchemist&lt;/em&gt; by Paulo Coelho, or at least a version of him that hasn&amp;rsquo;t quite made it to the ending and perhaps never does.</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>(Foolish) optimism</title>
        <link>https://vinayh.com/posts/2020-04-02/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 01:03:20 +0200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://vinayh.com/posts/2020-04-02/</guid>
        <description>Here are a few very brief and incomplete notes that I came up with while writing to a friend in defense of my optimism regarding the future of the US, slightly adapted.</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Quick reflection</title>
        <link>https://vinayh.com/posts/2020-04-01/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 14:54:42 +0200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://vinayh.com/posts/2020-04-01/</guid>
        <description>I thought I would at least take this chance to log my experience so far now that it&amp;rsquo;s been a week of consistent posts (and a few days of less-than-consistent ones).</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nature walk</title>
        <link>https://vinayh.com/posts/2020-03-31/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 22:25:51 +0200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://vinayh.com/posts/2020-03-31/</guid>
        <description>I joined my flatmates for a quick walk in the woods today upon one&amp;rsquo;s invitation, having sequestered myself in the apartment for days without direct sunlight and only the breeze afforded by my window.</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Family values</title>
        <link>https://vinayh.com/posts/2020-03-30/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 23:41:10 +0200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://vinayh.com/posts/2020-03-30/</guid>
        <description>I was fortunate enough to be able to participate in a video call last weekend that included much of my increasingly global extended family.</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Freeing</title>
        <link>https://vinayh.com/posts/2020-03-29/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 23:59:18 +0200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://vinayh.com/posts/2020-03-29/</guid>
        <description>I find it inevitable that I explore the freedom of my thoughts uninhibited, particularly as this blog is an exercise in voluntary writing.</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rejuvenation</title>
        <link>https://vinayh.com/posts/2020-03-27/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 23:43:42 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://vinayh.com/posts/2020-03-27/</guid>
        <description>There&amp;rsquo;s something rather wonderful about rediscovering a friendship with an old friend or family member that you haven&amp;rsquo;t talked to in a while.</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Global music</title>
        <link>https://vinayh.com/posts/2020-03-26/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 23:56:08 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://vinayh.com/posts/2020-03-26/</guid>
        <description>As part of better understanding what types of music fit my various mental states and moods, I have been trying to find music when reading or writing material that requires a little less cognitive load.</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Prioritizing</title>
        <link>https://vinayh.com/posts/2020-03-25/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 19:33:55 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://vinayh.com/posts/2020-03-25/</guid>
        <description>How does one even begin to prioritize and choose between longer-term undertakings spanning several months or more?</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lockdown</title>
        <link>https://vinayh.com/posts/2020-03-24/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 23:24:19 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://vinayh.com/posts/2020-03-24/</guid>
        <description>I finally decided to make the trek out of my apartment today to replenish on groceries after more than a week of quarantining myself, and in the midst of widespread self-quarantining to limit spread of the coronavirus.</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pride</title>
        <link>https://vinayh.com/posts/2020-03-23/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 23:33:50 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://vinayh.com/posts/2020-03-23/</guid>
        <description>I was in a conversation some few weeks ago with a friend in which they claimed to feel pride because of the country they were from, in contrast to many other places which handled the issue in question differently.</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Daily</title>
        <link>https://vinayh.com/posts/2020-03-22/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 16:32:25 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://vinayh.com/posts/2020-03-22/</guid>
        <description>I started this daily notes sub-blog to have a more frictionless way to post daily thoughts without the commitment of composing a full blog post.</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Belonging</title>
        <link>https://vinayh.com/posts/belonging/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 21:48:38 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://vinayh.com/posts/belonging/</guid>
        <description>Taking a moment to reflect on the value of feeling like you belong and are accepted for who you are.</description>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>